# Tyler Mayes - Junior Web Developer

317-851-7061 | tylermayes14@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

### **Profile**

Indiana based web developer, soldier, educator, and experienced leader - multi-talented, versatile young professional with experience in highly-effective conflict resolution and persuasive communication techniques. Hardworking and reliable with excellent attention to detail. Adept at operating in fast-paced environments and maintaining calm in challenging situations. Driven to exceed expectations and maximize satisfaction. Excels at working and building confident, organized, and knowledgeable coworkers, employees, and students.

## Experience

### DRUMLINE INSTRUCTOR, PERRY MERIDIAN HS, INDIANAPOLIS, IN - 04/2019-PRESENT

Provide leadership and instruction to grade 8-12 students studying music and playing various percussion instruments. Liaise with directors, teachers, and staff to ensure continuity of practice & development in rehearsal. Take a creative approach to mentoring individual students. Maintain students' progress by evaluating and adjusting strategies.

### INFANTRYMAN, US ARMY, DANVILLE, IN - 04/2018-PRESENT

Trained in combat, life saving techniques, and physical performance. Partake in combat patrols on foot and in vehicles. Evaluate terrain and record topographical information. Work & train in squads of 10-13 in modern combat scenarios. Trained & qualified in firing/assembling carbine rifles and assault weapons. Learn about leadership & teamwork through vigorous, high-stress training.

### **INFANTRY TEAM LEADER**

Directly responsible for the well being, physical readiness, morale, and discipline of 3-4 soldiers within a 13-man squad. Lead team of soldiers through modern combat scenarios. Responsible for the individual training and maintenance of their equipment, uniforms, and job knowledge.

#### LESSONS MANAGER, GUITAR CENTER, GREENWOOD, IN - 05/2018-04/2019

Managed Guitar Center's lesson department. Coordinated scheduling between students/ instructors. Created advertisements promoting the lessons program. Ensured student & instructor success by tracking student progress and discussing teaching techniques with instructors. Hosted/coordinated lessons sponsored events such as open houses, jam nights, and recitals. Oversaw a team of instructors and accommodated accordingly to their needs/wants.

#### **DRUM SALES ASSOCIATE**

Recommended merchandise based on customer needs. Interfaced with customers, determined needs, provided recommendations, and up-sell services. Increased purchase totals by recommending additional items/programs such as memberships and store sponsored credit cards. Described merchandise and explained product operation to customers. Maintained knowledge of current promotions, exchange guidelines, payment policies, and security practices.

DRUMLINE INSTRUCTOR, DECATUR CENTRAL HS, INDIANAPOLIS, IN - 05/2018-02/2019

Provided leadership and instruction to grade 8 thru 12 students studying music and playing various percussion instruments. Liaised with directors, teachers, and staff to ensure continuity of practice and development in rehearsal. Took a creative approach to mentoring individual students. Maintained students' progress by evaluating and adjusting strategies.

### Education

Eleven Fifty Academy, Indianapolis, IN - JavaScript Development – 09/2019-Present

Basic Combat Training/School of Infantry, Fort Benning, GA – 08/2018-12/2018

Franklin Central High School, Indianapolis, IN – High School Diploma – 08/2014-05/2018

# Skills

Web Development | Education | Sales -

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Bootstrap, Angular, React, Node
- API's, MVC, & REST applications
- Leadership, communication, organization

# Certifications

Self-Structured Development - Level 1, US Army, issued 2019

Good Manufacturing Practices, Westrock, issued 2019

# Awards & Decorations

Army Service Ribbon, awarded 11/2018

National Defense Ribbon, awarded 12/2018